{"1": {"question": "Finzi: What kind of song is this?", "correct": "An English art song", "incorrect": ["A Lied", "A pop song", "An instrumental song", "A British art song"]}, "2": {"question": "Finzi: How far back does the genre English art song go?", "correct": "Late sixteenth to early seventeenth centuries", "incorrect": ["Late seventeenth to early eighteenth centuries", "Late sixteenth to early eighteenth centuries", "Late fifteenth to early sixteenth centuries", "Back in my day"]}, "3": {"question": "Finzi: Lute songs by which composers are notable from the late sixteenth to early seventeenth centuries?", "correct": "John Dowland and Thomas Campion", "incorrect": ["John Dowland and Henry Purcell", "Ralph Vaughan Williams and Henry Purcell", "Michael Jackson and Thomas Campion", "John Dowland and William Walton"]}, "4": {"question": "Finzi: Whose works marked a high point in seventeenth century English music across all genres?", "correct": "Henry Purcell", "incorrect": ["Ralph Vaughan Williams", "Thomas Campion", "Arnold Bax", "Barack Obama"]}, "5": {"question": "Finzi: How did foreign influences come to dominate the musical landscape in England?", "correct": "The importation of Italian opera and in the works of Handel", "incorrect": ["Uncontrolled immigration", "Work opportunities attracting foreigners to England", "Serious self-esteem issues on the part of English composers (most of which fell into a deep depression)", "Their music was more appealing to audiences in England"]}, "6": {"question": "Finzi: The solo songs in England were dominantly developing where?", "correct": "From outside of England", "incorrect": ["In England", "Oceania", "Asia", "The Americas"]}, "7": {"question": "Finzi: The German tradition of the Lied was a large influence on the English art song. Which composers were part of that genre?", "correct": "Franz Schubert, Robert Schumann, Felix Mendelssohn, Johannes Brahms", "incorrect": ["Robert Schumman, Johannes Brahms, Johann Sebastian Bach, Franz Schubert", "Felix Mendehlssohn, Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, Johann Wolfgang Beethoven, Robert Schumann", "Franz Schubert, Roberto Schumann, Felix Mendelssohn, Johann's Bras", "Franz Schubert, Felix Mendelssohn, Johannes Brahms, William Shakespeare"]}, "8": {"question": "Finzi: What factors led to a period termed by some as the 'English musical Renaissance'?", "correct": "A growing sense of national awareness amongst English musicians, supported by a folk-song revival movement", "incorrect": ["A growing sense of national identity and confidence amongst musicians in England", "An increase in English composers in England at the time creating more music", "Foreign composers claiming to be English immigrating to England and composing masterpieces", "A growing sense of national awareness that encouraged people to write less music"]}, "9": {"question": "Finzi: What kinds of music were rediscovered in the 'English musical Renaissance'?", "correct": " 'Pre-Handelian' English music (court music) and British folk music", "incorrect": ["Jazz music, especially the elevator variety", "British folk music and renaissance music", "Renaissance music and 'Pre-Handelian' English music (court music)", "Pre-Bachian' English music and British folk music"]}, "10": {"question": "Finzi: Examples of twentieth century composers that were beneficiaries of the re-emergence of English music after foreign domination:", "correct": "Ralph Vaughan Williams, John Ireland, Arnold Bax, William Walton, Benjamin Britten", "incorrect": ["John Ireland, Benjamin Britten, Franz Schubert, Mark Walton, Arnold Bax", "William Walton, Ralph Vaughan Williams, Henry Purcell, Benjamin Britten, Arnold Bax", "Ralph Vaughan Williams, John Coltrane, Arnold Bax, Benjamin Britten, Miles Davis", "Ralph Vaughan Williams, John England, Arnold Bax, William Waton, Benjamin Britain"]}, "11": {"question": "Finzi: Examples of important English poets whose texts were set to music include:", "correct": "Shakespeare, Milton, Wordsworth, Coleridge, Hardy", "incorrect": ["Shakespeare, Dickens, Coleridge, Hardy, Wordsworth", "Keats, Milton, Shakespeare, Donne, Wordsworth", "Blake, Wordsworth, Hardy, Keats, Shakespeare", "John Lennon, Paul McCartney, Ringo Starr, George Harrison"]}, "12": {"question": "Finzi: What instrumentation is an art song comprised of?", "correct": "Solo voice and instrumental accompaniment", "incorrect": ["String orchestra and soloist", "Solo voice", "Solo instrument and instrumental accompaniment", "A chamber choir with a string quartet"]}, "13": {"question": "Finzi: How many short cycles of songs did Finzi compose?", "correct": "At least 8", "incorrect": ["8", "At least 24", "10", "16"]}, "14": {"question": "Finzi: From which English poet is Finzi's Let us garlands bring's text from?", "correct": "Shakespeare", "incorrect": ["Coleridge", "Hardy", "Milhouse", "Wordsworth"]}, "15": {"question": "Finzi: Which of Shakespeare's plays is O mistress mine from?", "correct": "Twelfth Night", "incorrect": ["Macbeth", "Romeo and Juliet", "A Midsummer Night's Dream", "Hamlet"]}, "16": {"question": "Finzi: How many six-line stanzas (sextains) are there in the text?", "correct": "2", "incorrect": ["4", "6", "17.3", "8"]}, "17": {"question": "Finzi: What kind of rhyme scheme do the sextains have?", "correct": "aabccb", "incorrect": ["abacad", "x", "ababab", "abcabc"]}, "18": {"question": "Finzi: How is the form of the song best described?", "correct": "Semi-strophic", "incorrect": ["Strophic", "Through-composed", "Sonata form", "Binary form"]}, "19": {"question": "Finzi: What happens to the cadence at the end of each stanza?", "correct": "It is elided with the commencement of the next piano section", "incorrect": ["It is replaced with a sequence that leads to the commencement of the next piano section", "It is an imperfect cadence which leads nicely to the next section", "It is repeated except changed so it becomes a 'second go'", "The performer forgets about it because they have a mental blank and can't remember how to play their instrument"]}, "20": {"question": "What is a strophic song?", "correct": "Each stanza is set to the same music", "incorrect": ["No substantial repitition of music for each stanza", "A song without words", "A song with a very repetitive melody", "A song with a very repetitive harmony"]}, "21": {"question": "What is a through-composed song?", "correct": "No substantial repitition of music for each stanza", "incorrect": ["Each stanza is set to the same music", "A song without words", "A very thoroughly composed piece of music", "A song that has little to no repitition in it"]}, "22": {"question": "What is a semi-strophic song?", "correct": "Between strophic and through-composed, bit of the same music but also different in each stanza", "incorrect": ["A shorter strophic song", "A song with motifs and ideas that seem to match each other but are not the same", "A song with a repetitive melody that sometimes introduces new ideas", "A song that has verses that are the same as each other"]}, "23": {"question": "Where would the music be the same usually in a semi-strophic song?", "correct": "At the beginning of each stanza, being the most logical way to express identity", "incorrect": ["At the end of each stanza, being the best way to finish", "In the middle of each stanza because that is where the listener feels secure and understands the music", "At the beginning of the first stanza and the end of the second stanza", "At the end of the first stanza and the beginning of the second stanza"]}, "24": {"question": "Finzi: Which other composers have used this same text from Twelfth Night?", "correct": "Thomas Morley, Sullivan, Vaughan Williams, Charles Villers Stanford, Margaret Sutherland", "incorrect": ["Thomas Morley, Charles Dickens, Vaughan Williams, Margaret Sutherland", "Donald Trump, Vaughan Williams, Charles Villers Stanford, Sullivan, Thomas Morley", "Vaughan Williams, Shakespeare, Sullivan, Thomas Morley, Rudy Giuliani, Margaret Sutherland", "Purcell, Sullivan, Margaret Sutherland, Finzi, Thomas Morley"]}, "25": {"question": "Finzi: What key is O mistress mine in?", "correct": "Eb major", "incorrect": ["Bb major", "E major", "C minor", "Db major"]}, "26": {"question": "Finzi: Does O mistress mine ever modulate to another key?", "correct": "No", "incorrect": ["Yes", "Yes, to all 7 billion of them", "Nothing is impossible if you put your mind to it", "Definitely"]}, "27": {"question": "Finzi: How can the mood throughout most of the song be described?", "correct": "Light-hearted and jaunty", "incorrect": ["Dysphoric and delusional", "Anxious and irritable", "Cheerful and bright", "Melancholic and reflective"]}, "28": {"question": "Finzi: O mistress mine is mostly diatonic except for where?", "correct": "The final bars of each stanza where modal mixture is introduced", "incorrect": ["The opening bars of each stanza where the ideas are being introduced", "The middle of each stanza", "The bridges between the stanzas", "China because they banned the import of diatonic"]}, "29": {"question": "Finzi: Where does the mood change to become more reflective?", "correct": "At the end of each stanza with the modal mixture", "incorrect": ["At the beginning of each stanza", "At the beginning and the end of each stanza", "When it nears the end of its life", "In the middle of each stanza to add an element of surprise"]}, "30": {"question": "Finzi: What does the right hand primarily consist of?", "correct": "A free, two-part texture with occasional thickening", "incorrect": ["A free, three-part texture with occasional thinning", "A free flowing melody that occasionally thickens", "A restricted, two-part texture with occasional thickening", "Five fingers and a palm"]}, "31": {"question": "Finzi: What does the left hand primarily consist of?", "correct": "A staccato 'vamping' accompaniment", "incorrect": ["A staccato unpredictable accompaniment", "Long sustained notes from the chords", "A walking bass line", "A free flowing countermelody"]}, "32": {"question": "Finzi: What is a consistent feature present in the left hand accompaniment?", "correct": "A downward stepping motion from the second beat of the bar to the first beat of next bar", "incorrect": ["An upward stepping motion from the second beat of the bar to the first beat of the next bar", "A downward stepping motion from the first to the second beat of the bar", "Dominant tenths", "An upward stepping motion from the first to the second beat of the bar"]}, "33": {"question": "Finzi: How do the interlude and hte postlude compare to the introduction?", "correct": "They are quite similar", "incorrect": ["They substantially differ as they share no common music", "They are identical", "They are not related to each other in any way", "They are much shorter, but make up for it in dynamics"]}, "34": {"question": "Finzi: Are the musical material from the vocal line and the piano part dependent on each other?", "correct": "No they are relatively independent", "incorrect": ["Yes because they constantly imitate each other", "Yes due to how the parts interlock and play together", "No but they do share a lot of the same ideas, so actually yes", "Yes because they are both in a sticky financial situation due to the Coronavirus pandemic"]}, "35": {"question": "Finzi: What type of text setting is the text?", "correct": "Syllabic", "incorrect": ["Neumatic", "Melismatic", "Problematic", "Dolichocephalic"]}, "36": {"question": "Finzi: What is accountable for the subtle rhythm changes from stanza to stanza?", "correct": "Natural declamation", "incorrect": ["Rubato", "Natural tempo variation", "Natural emphasisation", "The incapable musician not being able to tap their foot"]}, "37": {"question": "Finzi: How do the first lines of each stanza compare rhythmically?", "correct": "Different in their natural speech rhythms and have a different number of syllables", "incorrect": ["They are the same", "They share some rhythmic groupings", "Different number of syllables but similar speech rhythms", "Different in their natural speech rhythms but same number of syllables"]}, "38": {"question": "Finzi: How does the piano accompaniment for the first lines of each stanza compare?", "correct": "It is identical", "incorrect": ["They are in different keys", "They are at different tempos", "They are similar with a few note changes", "The piano isn't playing at that part, get pranked Laugh Out LOUD"]}, "39": {"question": "Finzi: Does the highly flexible, natural text setting remain consistent throughout the song?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Maybe", "Possibly", "Naaaaaaaaaaah"]}, "40": {"question": "Finzi: At what points in the stanzas are the piano accompaniment and the melody similar?", "correct": "At the beginning and nearing the end", "incorrect": ["In the middle of both stanzas", "In the final line of both stanzas", "At the beginning of both stanzas", "Nowhere, because its a circle"]}, "41": {"question": "Finzi: Where is the only instance of direct imitation between the voice and the piano found?", "correct": "At the very final line in each stanza", "incorrect": ["The first line of each stanza", "The middle of the second stanza", "At the end of the song", "The beginning of the final stanza"]}, "42": {"question": "Finzi: What changes occur in the final two lines in each stanza?", "correct": "Harmony shifts to parallel minor, accompaniment texture changes, pace slows, dramatic dynamic contrast", "incorrect": ["Harmony shifts to parallel minor, pace quickens, overall texture becomes more dense and dynamics increase", "Harmony shifts up a major fifth, pace slows, accompaniment texture changes, dynamic contrast", "Pace quickens, accompaniment texture thins, pace slows, dynamics dramatically softer", "Nothing is changed here"]}}